export const questions = [
    {
        category: "Docker",
        question: "What is the primary function of a Dockerfile?",
        options: [
            "Defines the base image for a container",
            "Manages container networking",
            "Orchestrates container deployment",
            "Stores container logs",
        ],
        correct: "Defines the base image for a container",
    },
    {
        category: "AWS",
        question: "Which AWS service is primarily used for compute instances?",
        options: ["S3", "EC2", "RDS", "Lambda"],
        correct: "EC2",
    },
    {
        category: "Kubernetes",
        question:
            "What is the control plane component responsible for managing the state of the cluster?",
        options: ["Kubelet", "Pod", "Controller Manager", "Etcd"],
        correct: "Controller Manager",
    },
    {
        category: "React",
        question: "What is the core concept of JSX in React?",
        options: [
            "A templating language",
            "A JavaScript library",
            "A CSS preprocessor",
            "A virtual DOM",
        ],
        correct: "A virtual DOM",
    },
    {
        category: "Angular",
        question: "What is the architecture of Angular applications?",
        options: [
            "Model-View-Controller (MVC)",
            "Model-View-ViewModel (MVVM)",
            "Component-based",
            "Server-Side Rendering (SSR)",
        ],
        correct: "Component-based",
    },
    {
        category: "Python",
        question:
            "Which data structure in Python is used to store key-value pairs?",
        options: ["List", "Tuple", "Dictionary", "Set"],
        correct: "Dictionary",
    },
    {
        category: "Docker",
        question: "How do you create a new Docker image?",
        options: [
            "docker run",
            "docker build",
            "docker commit",
            "docker image create",
        ],
        correct: "docker build",
    },
    {
        category: "AWS",
        question: "Which AWS service is primarily used for object storage?",
        options: ["S3", "EC2", "RDS", "Lambda"],
        correct: "S3",
    },
    {
        category: "Kubernetes",
        question: "What is a Pod in Kubernetes?",
        options: [
            "A group of containers",
            "A single container",
            "A cluster of nodes",
            "A deployment strategy",
        ],
        correct: "A group of containers",
    },
    {
        category: "React",
        question: "What is the purpose of state in React components?",
        options: [
            "To store data that can change over time",
            "To define the component's structure",
            "To manage component lifecycle",
            "To handle user interactions",
        ],
        correct: "To store data that can change over time",
    },
];
